Here's a simple improve warm up exercise.
It’s a nice icebreaker for a group.
It’s called Zip Zap Zop.
And one of the things it’s good at is its good for helping people mess up in front of each other.
It causes for a lot of mistakes and that get people loosened up and just feeling goofy.
So it’s a lot like the game Pass the Clap.
You're going to get everybody in the circle and one person's going to make eye contact with someone else in the circle, and they're going to clap at them, at the same time they're going to say the word zip, zip, o.k.
That person is going to look at somebody else and they're going to clap at them and they're going to say zap.
That person's going to look at somebody else and say zop.
And it’s going to start back over, zip zap zop, zip zap zop.
So people are clapping, ding ding ding ding ding, around the circle and they're saying zip zap zop, zip zap zop.
And you can see already I'm just going to flub it up when you're sort of zip zap zop zop zip and then you get to celebrate every time someone makes a mistake.
So this is a game that should be played fast.
If you're playing zip zap zop, zip..zap...you're doing something wrong.
So you should play it fast enough that people are messing up and that the words are getting tripped up and focus people on making eye contact with each other and delivering the word straight to them.
So that is the improv exercise Zip Zap Zop.